Melvin Zaaijer

% (+31)6 30 62 76 92

contact@melvinzaaijer.com

Pijnacker, ZH

im in/melvinzaaijer

melvinzaaijer.com

SUMMARY

With 8+ years of experience in technology consulting and project delivery, my expertise lies in e-commerce, content, and digital marketing. I excel in fast-paced environments, specialising in designing, developing, and rolling out complex IT transformation projects. Leading diverse teams, I prioritise user centricity and adaptability to meet business goals. I am also experienced in people management, driving product roadmap, financial management, staffing, and collaborating with sales to explore new opportunities. Visit my website for more details and visuals!

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE (selected)

Delivery Lead / Project Manager

GRANDVISION 2021-2023

Accelerate online transformation realising a global commerce and content platform.

- Responsible for 7+ Million revenue and 20+ FTE at peak times including 20% upsell in people on client contract FY22.
- MACH Architecture (CommerceTools, Bloomreach, React.Js/Next.Js, Node.Js, Bynder, Algolia, Adyen, Cloudflare, Boomi and more).
- In charge of resourcing, staffing, capacity planning, project planning, finance, client(s) relationship management and delivery.

Content Capability Lead

ACCENTURE INTERNAL

2022-Current

Build a practice that is specialised in content platform realisation.

- Lead a team of 7+ people to support and build content capabilities in platform implementation, content migration and change enablement.
- Contribute to a total of 10M sales pipeline and successfully capture 2M sales by driving workshops, solutioning, pricing, staffing, stakeholders and procurement updates.
- Designing and executing individual career tracks around trainings, certifications, projects and (software) partnerships.

Product Owner / Scrum Master

GRANDVISION 2019-2021

Introducing a global MACH architecture including dynamic CMS to meet and exceed the customer expectations.

- As a PO I was responsible for defining and prioritizing the product backlog, ensuring that the team is building the right product for the customer within the My Account domain. The new customer experience is driving ~18% increase of digital influenced store sales.
- In my Scrum Master role, I was responsible for the sprint delivery and guidance of 2 teams while following the Agile principles and removing any obstacles that may hinder their progress in a large program with 8 scrum teams.

Lead Business Analyst

SAMSUNG 2017-2018

Transforming online sales worldwide by implementing a eCommerce platform that allow customers to buy through OmniChannel.

- Provide strategic direction, mentorship, and guidance to a team of business analysts
- Perform fit-gap analysis between local subsidiary requirements and global platform to provide customer focused solutions with minimal adjustments
- Facilitate stakeholders workshops to present platform capabilities and gather requirements for new countries roll-outs
- Collaborate with architect and developers to detail out user stories and provide high level estimations



ACHIEVEMENT

Realizing improved customer experience

~150M annual commerce sales (growing from 0,01% to 10%) online revenue

Champion 2022-2023

As captain of the basketbal team I'm extremely proud we became division champions.

STRENGHTS

Gallup

Ideation, Relator, Developer Arranger, Strategic

Peoples Advocate

Care deeply for all of our people and engage strongly to demonstrate culture, inclusion and diversity.

EXPERTISE & INDUSTRIES

- eCommerce
- Content Management Systems
- Stakeholder Management
- Application Delivery and Rollout
- Agile/Scrum
- Customer-oriented
- Coach / Mentor
- (Optical) Retail
- Consumer goods & services
- Telecomunications

CERTIFICATIONS

- SAFe (POPM) Product Owner / Product Manager
- Accenture Delivery Lead
- UX Management NNG
- SAP Hybris Commerce Business Analyst 6.0
- SAFe Agilist

LANGUAGES

Dutch (Nederlands)

Vative

English

Full professional proficiency

EDUCATION

MSc. Design For Interaction

Delft University of Technology

BSc. Industrial Design Engineering

Delft University of Technology